本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
来月になたら期末テストあるのわかるよね
As I'm sure you are aware,
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
you have final exams starting next month.
You are aware, right?
わかるよね
So, I think you know what I'm getting at,
で予想はついてるかもしれないけど
赤点の教科があた場合
but if you fail any subjects...
Supplementary classes will be held on weekends.
補習は週末だよ
If necessary, it will be held during summer break as well.
場合によては夏休みにも入る
遠征は物理的に無理なんじゃないかね
Going to the away games would be physically impossible.
おいどこにも逃げられないぞ
Hey! There's nowhere to run!
Ennoshita, grab them!
縁下捕まえろ
Got it!
Fail... Fail...
赤赤点て何点ですか
What counts as a failing grade?
That's your question?!
そから
Kageyama isn't breathing!
影山が息してません
Since we said we're going to stay on the team,
俺達も部活続けるて言たからにはそれなりの成績出さないとな
we have to at least make decent grades.
You shouldn't fail your finals.
赤点はないでしょ
Nope.
ないね
M-Maybe if we beg the vice principal as hard as we can...
教教頭先生に一生懸命頼めばきと
You should try as hard as you can to not fail your finals instead.
まずは一生懸命赤点を避けなよ
Even if we get the vice principal's permission,
教頭先生の承諾はもらえても
if any of you have to take supplementary classes,
those will take priority.
補習になた場合そちが優先だよ
Coach!
W-Well, this isn't something you're gonna be able to avoid as a student.
ままあ学生である以上は避けて通れんよな
そんな
But...
根性だ気持ちが大事だぞ
Don't give up! You need to believe you can do it!
Mind over matter?!
精神論
No, that's fine.
いやこの際それでもいいです教えてください
Please teach me!
Hinata, I didn't really want to bring this up,
日向よこれはあまり言いたくはなかたが
この俺が勉強できるタイプに見えるか
but do I look like someone who got good grades?
Hinata, I'm sure you don't have to worry this much about it.
日向そこまで思い詰めなくても多分大丈夫だよ
I've never gotten a double-digit score on any of my quizzes.
俺小テスト２ケタ以上の点数ほとんど取たことないですけど
Will I still be okay?
大丈夫ですか
Huh?
Hey! Praying isn't going to help, you two!
おいお前ら菩薩顔やめろ
They can do it if they try. They can do it if they try.
やればできるやればできる
先生もしかりしろ
Pull yourself together, Mr. Takeda!
阿鼻叫喚
Ah, the sound of anguish.
狼狽えるな
Get a hold of yourselves!
テストまでまだ時間はあるんだ
We still have time until finals.
There's no way we can play our best without these four idiots!
このバカ４人抜きで烏野のマクスが発揮できるか
Not a chance!
いやできない
嬉しいような悲しいような
I don't know if I'm flattered or insulted...
We're gonna do this.
やてやる全員で東京行てやる
We're all gonna go to Tokyo.
Episode Two:
Direct Sunlight
Listen up, you guys.
いいかお前らまずお前らがこれから絶対に守ることは
The one thing that you're
going to promise me right now...
is that you will not fall asleep in class.
授業中に寝ないこと
That's top priority?
そからなのか
Staying up late through sheer willpower.
根性だけでいきなり徹夜
Screwing up in your classes and in practice.
日中の授業も部活もグズグズ
It's all completely absurd!
なんてことは以ての外だ
Right...
We're heading out.
お先です
R-Right. Good job.
お疲れ
It'll be all right.
大丈夫そもそも高校入試はパスできたわけだしさ
I mean, you guys passed your high school entrance exams.
Suga!
スガさん
If you fall asleep in class, you'd better be prepared for the consequences.
まあこれで授業中寝てたらマジ覚悟しとけよ
影山
Kageyama.
What? No way!
嫌だ
You have no right to be picky!
おいワガママ言うな
赤点取たら遠征行けないんだぞ
If we fail our finals, we can't go on the trip!
We're playing Nekoma!
音駒だぞ東京の強豪がゴロゴロなんだぞ
And all the powerhouses in Tokyo are gonna be there!
You're okay with not being able to go?!
行けなくてもいいのか
ウシワカに最強のセタになるて言てたじゃねか
You told Ushiwaka that you'd become the best setter!
Foot of the Slope
I'm actually surprised that Kageyama's grades are bad.
影山も勉強できないて意外だよな
He seems pretty smart.
頭の回転速そうなのに
Hinata's grades don't surprise me at all, though.
日向は見たまんまだけど
I'm sure all that's in his head is volleyball.
頭ん中完全にバレのことだけなんでしょ
Tsukishima!
月島
Sir.
Help us study...
勉強教えてくれ
Please.
What? No.
嫌だけど
Just, like, an hour each day!
１日数十分とかそれか勉強法チョコととかでも
Or maybe tell us how to study...
I think it'd be all right if you did a little bit before and after practice.
部活前後にちょとくらいならいいんじゃない
Hey, isn't it unfair for you to make the little one do all the begging?
ちょと小さい方にばか頼ませるて卑怯じゃないの
I'm talking to you, big guy.
そちのでかい方
影山頼めよ
Kageyama, ask him!
教えてください
Please teach us.
What was that?
勉強教えてください
Please teach us how to study.
I don't think I quite heard you.
よく聞こえないんですけど
Studying! I'm asking you to teach us how, you punk!
勉強をォォ教えてくださいコラァァ
Shut the hell up! You're disturbing the neighborhood!
うるせぇぞお前ら近所迷惑だ
すすません
S-Sorry!
Why am I getting yelled at?
なんで僕まで
Sorry.
すみません
It's okay. Thank you, though.
ううん　ありがとう
Shimizu!
清水先輩
I found someone in another class that hasn't joined a club yet.
他のクラスのまだ部活やてないやつ探してみました
ありがとう
Thanks!
Yes, no!
はいいいえ
"Yes, no"?
She smiled!
笑た
U-Um, doing all of the manager's duties by yourself must be hard, right?
ああのマネジャの仕事てやぱり一人だと大変ですよね
If there's anything a first-year can do, I'd be happy to help.
一年でやれること手伝いますけど
We're going to the Spring Tournament!
We third-years are going to be gone after the next tournament.
私達三年は次の大会が終わればいなくなる
Watching all of you get better,
強くなる皆を見て来年とか再来年のこと改めて考えてみたんだ
it made me rethink about what'll happen next year and the year after that.
There are still things I need to do too.
私も自分の仕事をやておかなくちゃ
I-I'll gladly help!
手伝います
ありがとうでも勉強優先ね
Thanks, but you should focus on studying.
That and practice, of course.
それと練習もね
Everyone's looking forward to the greatest decoy.
皆「最強の囮」に期待してるから
Right!
All right, let's move on to the next one.
はいささと次
Hinata, what's the first answer to question 6?
日向問六の一つ目は
For this, you do this to get this.
ここはこうでこう
Question six: Please insert the correct word or phrase that goes in the parentheses to correctly complete the idiom.
問六次の括弧に当てはまる語句を入れことわざを完成させなさい
This idiom expresses that even ruthless people can show compassion or even cry at times.
無慈悲なものにも時に慈悲の心から涙を流すことがあるということわざ
Even ogres can be moved to...
鬼の目にも
...an iron club?
金ぼう
Ow, my eyes!
痛い目が
Hey, how could you do that to the ogre?
お前鬼に酷いんじゃないか
「鬼に金棒」だと思たの問題文は読んでないのかな
You're thinking of another idiom.
Did you not read the explanation?
うせぇなもう
Oh, shut up.
You probably saw the word "ogre," didn't read the rest, and just wrote the first thing that came to mind.
鬼て見て問題もよく読まないでガて書いちゃたんでしょ
You really are a simpleton.
ホント単細胞
Yeah. You need to calm down.
そうだお前はもうちょと落ち着けそそかしいんだよ
You're too careless.
お前らなんで一言余計なの
Do you all have to comment on it?!
You're one to talk, Kageyama.
影山も人のこと言えないんだけど
Aren't you even worse off than Hinata overall?
全体的に日向よりできてないんじゃないの
You should at least memorize
English vocabulary by yourself.
英単語の暗記くらいは自分で何とかしなよ
Why would Japanese people
be able to understand English?
日本人に英語がわかるか
じゃあ東京行きは諦めるんだね
Then you should give up on going to Tokyo.
Kageyama.
影山
B Quick.
Ｂクイク
ＡＣセタ前の時間差
A, C, delayed attack in front of the setter,
left-side back row attack,
レフトバクアタク
Ｄ平行セミセタ後ろの時間差
D, parallel, semi, delayed attack behind the setter.
速
Man, that's fast.
How long did it take you to memorize those?
これどのくらいで覚えた
I think it was the same day we were taught them?
教えてもらた日スかね
Then I won't let you use "I can't
memorize the words" as an excuse.
それで暗記ができないとは言わせないからな
C-Crap.
いかん
I-I'm not gonna lose to you, Kageyama!
影山には負けね
All right. Let's go to my place after practice on Saturday.
よしじゃあ土曜部活の後うちな
Sounds good.
よしゃ
I'm not gonna lose to them, either!
先輩にも負けね
Like I said, you really need to calm down.
だから君はもう少し落ち着きなての
Nishinoya, let me see your quiz from yesterday.
西谷昨日の小テストを出して
おやつ
Snacks!
For Japanese, the answer is basically found somewhere within the problem text.
国語は基本的に文章の中に答えがあるからよく読めばわかるはずで
So if you read the passage carefully...
Question 3: Copy the sentence from the passage that most exemplifies the two contradictory feelings Norio has.
問三「紀男」の矛盾した二つの気持ちを最も良く表している一文を
文中から抜き出しなさい
もと男らしく生きろ紀男
Live more like a man, Norio!
The problem says you have to copy a sentence from the passage!
文中から抜き出せて書いてあんじゃん問題も紀男も無視すんなよ
Don't ignore both the problem and Norio!
You're so awesome, Noya.
ノヤさんかけぇぜ
You're good at memorization, aren't you, Nishinoya?
暗記ならいけるだろ西谷
Leave the four-character idioms to me!
E
Head
stand
四字熟語任せろ
That won't be on the exam!
それはテストに出るやつじゃないから
Ugh, are you guys actually studying?
あんた達勉強してんの
Are you feeling okay?
大丈夫
What'd you mean by that?
大丈夫てなんだよ
Saeko! Hey there!
冴子姉さんチス
Hey, Yuu! You're looking cool, as always.
おお夕今日も格好いいな
Thanks!
あざす
P-Pardon the intrusion.
おお邪魔してます
You're totally fine.
どうぞどうぞ
どら姉ちゃんが教えてやろうかオラ
Hey, how about your big sister teaching you something, punk?
Shut up!
うせな脳ミソの出来は一緒なんだからムダだろ
You're just as dumb as me, so there's no point.
Hey, I got into college on my first try, you know.
おい現役女子大生ナメんなよ
You only go to your job and practice!
バイトと練習しかしてねぇだろ
Sh-Shut up! I'm just working hard when you aren't watching!
う　うるせぇ見えないとこで努力してんだよ
田中の姉ちゃんかけぇな
Tanaka's sister is so cool.
Yeah.
Don't come crying to me later!
後で泣きついても知んないかんな
練習て何の
Practice? What kind?
Taiko drums.
和太鼓
She's getting a team together.
チム作てんだよ祭りとかになると張り切てんぞ
When it's festival time, she goes all out.
Wow. How cool.
かけぇ
Viva chest wraps!
ビバサラシ
All right, let's do this.
よしほらやるぞ東京行くんだろ
You're going to Tokyo, aren't you?
はい縁下先生
Yes, Mr. Ennoshita!
Sender: Hinata Shouyou
Tomorrow!!!
Tokyo's starting their interhigh prelims
tomorrow, right?! Do your best!
Tokyo's starting their interhigh prelims tomorrow, right?!
東京は明日からＩＨ予選なんだよながんばれ
Do your best!
Yeah, gradually...
You guys are coming to Tokyo, right?
まあぼちぼち翔陽達はコチ来るんでしょ
Let's play jump rope, Bro!
兄ちゃんなわとびしよ
Nacchan, your brother's said he's gonna study!
夏ちゃん兄ちゃん勉強するんだて
Aw...
We're totally going! We're gonna win this time, just you wait!
All right! I'm gonna go to Tokyo!
Sending
よし行くぜ東京
翔陽うるさい
Shouyou, be quiet!
Faculty Office
Goodness, Tanaka from class 1...
１組の田中最近授業中に寝てないだけじゃなくて
Not only is he not sleeping in class anymore, he's been asking questions after class.
授業後に質問に来たりするんですよ
Same with Nishinoya from class 3!
３組の西谷もですよやればできるんですなぁ
Looks like they can do it if they try.
Maybe the Tokyo away games are becoming a reality.
東京遠征が現実的になてきたかも
That just leaves Shimizu's part.
あとは清水さんの方か
I wonder if it's going well.
うまくいたかな
あのちょといいかな
Hey, do you have a moment?
Karasuno High School Boys' Volleyball Team
Seeking Members
& Manager!
Soliciting for a new manager...
新マネジャの勧誘
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
Wow... She's so pretty.
美人
In the interhigh preliminaries recently, we were dead even against Aoba Jousai, a team that went to the finals.
こないだのインタハイ予選もね
So, she's a third-year.
三年生か
She's so pretty.
美人
青葉城西ていう決勝まで行たところとほぼ互角に戦たんだけど
The mole by her mouth is sexy.
口元のホクロがセクシ
So pretty.
美人
Though we do have quite a few troublemakers, I'm sure you'll find that they're a team you want to root for.
ちょと問題児多いんだけどね
Her hair is silky-smooth.
髪艶さら
でもきと応援したくなるチムだと思うんだ
Everyone's totally staring at her too.
周りの人もすごい見てる
Why don't we try a trial membership?
でねまずは仮入部て形でどうかな
Huh?! Sure!
本当ありがとう
Really?! Thank you so much!
I'll come by again after school.
じゃ放課後また来ますね
新しい人見つかたんすね
So you found a new person!
What's up?
何何
なんすか
What's going on?
Um, she's joining the team on a trial basis as the new manager.
えと新しいマネジャとして仮入部の
I-I'm Yachi Hitoka!
や谷地仁花です
Seriously? That's awesome!
マジかすげぇ
Nice job, Shimizu!
さすがき清水先輩
So cute...
可愛い
１年生
You're a first-year?
い１年５組であります
I-I'm in Class 1-5, sir!
"Sir"?
あります
Asahi, back up a bit.
旭ちょと引込め
Huh?
Hey!
こらお前ら失礼だろその見方
Don't stare like that! It's rude.
よかたなこれで来年もマネジャいるな
Thank goodness.
Now there'll be a manager next year too.
Yes!
Sh-She hasn't actually joined yet.
まだ仮だから
I suddenly asked her today to come by before her committee meeting,
後今日は突然お願いして急遽委員会の仕事の前に来てもらたから
so she's just dropping in to say hi today.
今日は顔見せだけ
よ宜しくお願いしゃす
I-It's a pleasure to meet you!
しゃす
Same!
Could you not surround her like that until she's more comfortable?
慣れるまでは取り囲んでの挨拶はやめて
おお邪魔しました
S-Sorry for the intrusion.
Shimizu.
清水新しいマネジャ勧誘してくれたのか
So you were looking for a new manager, huh?
Yes.
I thought we didn't get enough responses when we tried to find people in April.
4月にやた勧誘は全然足りなかたなて思て
烏野がこれからもと強くなるために
I thought it was important to find someone to carry on as manager,
マネの仕事もちゃんと引き継いでいかなくちゃて思た
especially with Karasuno getting so much stronger.
清水さん
Shimizu!
潔子さん
Kiyoko!
I just came on a whim, but there were so many big guys!
勢いで来ちゃたけどでかい人いぱいだ
What am I going to do tomorrow?
明日どうしよう
あんな美人の隣に２分近く立てしまた
I stood next to that pretty lady for like two minutes!
ファンの人とかに暗殺されたらどうしよう
What if her fans try to kill me?!
どうしたの
What's the matter?
Blond hair and pierced ears!
金髪にピアスこんな人までファンなんて
Even a guy like this is a fan of hers?!
I-I'm going to be murdered!
こ殺される
What? Murdered...
お腹すいた
I'm starving.
Class 1-4
Let's go to Foot of the Slope!
坂ノ下行こう
部活前後だけて話だたよねね
Didn't we agree it was going to be
only right before and after practice?
Right?
But the English teacher, Mr. Yoshida, wasn't around—
だて英語の吉田先生いなかたんだもん
営業時間に出直してきてください
Please come back during business hours.
Class 1-4
Damn it, Tsukishima's so stingy.
クソけち月島けち島
Stingyshima!
I have to do something...
何とかせねば
Hinata!
日向
You're gonna teach me, Yamaguchi?
山口が教えてくれんの
Sorry, I suck at English.
ごめん俺英語だめだ
Remember the potential manager who came yesterday?
昨日のさマネ候補で来てた子いたじゃん
She said she was in class 5,
so she might be good at studying.
あの子５組て言てたから勉強得意かもよ
That's right. Classes 4 and 5 are the advanced classes.
そうか４５組進学クラスだもんな
What should I do after school?
放課後どうしよかなバレ部か
The volleyball team, huh?
Yachi!
谷地さん
Pardon us.
失礼します
Huh? What? Some guys from the volleyball team?
昨日のバレ部の
What should I do? What do they want?
どうしよう何だろう自己紹介されたけ
Did they introduce themselves to me yet?
Their names... What were their names again?
名前名前何だけ
一度聞いた名前も覚えられないなんて
How could I have forgotten them already?
名前も覚えられんのか
You can't even remember names?!
I won't be able to make it in society and lose my job...
社会でやていけず失業
I'll be out cold in the streets,
and in the end sell off my internal organs...
路頭に迷て
臓器売買
俺１組の日向翔陽
I'm Hinata Shouyou from class 1!
This is Kageyama.
これ影山
Hey.
ちわす
ちちわす
H-Hey.
Yachi, do you like studying?
谷地さん勉強好き
I don't hate it.
嫌いじゃないけど
Could you teach me this English?
英語これ教えてください
You should ask her too, Kageyama!
影山頼めよ
Please teach us.
教えてください
来月のテストで赤点取ると東京遠征にいけなくなちゃうんだよ
If we fail any tests next month, we won't be able to go to the Tokyo away games!
So we've been getting tutored by a tall guy with glasses named Tsukishima...
だから月島つめがねのぽに教えてもらてんだけど
なんでできない
Why can't you do this?
最近俺と影山がバカ過ぎていらいらしててさ
But he's been getting mad lately because Kageyama and I are too stupid for him.
He doesn't scare me.
あんなやつ別に怖くねぇから
優しく教えてもらえるほうがいいだろう
But it'd be better if someone nice taught us, right?
わ私でよければ
I-If you think I'm good enough...
本当に
Really?!
Yeah.
でも果たしてめがねのぽさんより優しく教えられるかどうか
But I'm not sure if I can be nicer than the tall guy with glasses.
You definitely don't have to worry about that.
それは絶対心配ないよ
Wow!
すげぇなるほどすげぇ
I see! Wow!
いやあの
Oh, it's nothing...
Your notes are really easy to read, Yachi! And you draw really well too!
谷地さんのノトてすごい見やすいね絵もうめぇ
My mom works at a design firm,
so she's always been picky about things like this.
お母さんがデザインの会社やてて昔からそういうことにうるさくて
Oh, if you leave a space here, it'll be easier to fill in later.
ここの空間取といたほうが後から書き込めていいよ
Also, if you use only a few colors, it won't get confusing.
後色数は少ないほうが混乱しないしそれと
And...
I'm sorry! I was writing all over your notebook!
ごめん人のノト勝手に
Oh, I see... You're amazing!
そうかなるほどさすが
I-It's n-nothing... Nothing at all...
そそんそんなそん
So, Hinata Shouyou...
日向くんは
Just Hinata's fine.
日向でいいよ
ひ日向は勉強嫌い
D-Do you not like studying, Hinata?
嫌いずと座てんのがもうつらい
I hate it.
Sitting for a long time like this sucks.
But aren't you working hard so that you can go on this trip to Tokyo?
でも頑張るのはその東京遠征に行くため
そう東京の強豪とがつり練習試合すんだ
Yeah! We're gonna have practice matches
with all the powerhouse schools from Tokyo!
That's amazing.
すごいね私そんなふうに何か本気でやたことないや
I've never been that serious about anything before.
There's this school called Nekoma High School in Tokyo, and the setter for their team is super-smart.
駒高校てのがあて
そこのセタがすげぇ賢くて
The captain with the rooster head is,
like, huge and evil-looking.
トサカみたいな頭の主将がなんかでかいし悪そうで
後レシブがすごくて何打てもびゃて拾て
And there's a guy that's totally awesome at digging out one receive after another like "foom"!
音駒のリベロすげぇよな
Nekoma's libero is awesome.
He's on par with Nishinoya.
Setter?
西谷さんに匹敵する
セタトサカリベロポジションかな
すげぇやついぱいるの
There are a lot of amazing guys!
Rooster head? Libero?
東京じゃなく県内には
Not just in Tokyo, but even in our prefecture.
Are these positions?
青葉城西てとこの大王様とか
There's the Great King over at Aoba Jousai,
絶対王者て言われるウシワカとか
Ushiwaka, who people call the greatest of all time,
伊達工の１９０センチの鉄壁とか
and Date Tech's Iron Wall that's 190 cm tall!
１９０センチ
190 centimeters?!
Um... Hinata, are you a manager too?
あの日向もマネジャ
Why?
なんで
バレてでかい人がやるのかと思て
I thought only tall people played volleyball,
and the team was full of tall guys.
バレ部の人もでかい人多かたし
I may be short, b-but I'm a starter!
小さいけどお俺一応レギュラなんだかんな
なんてこた
Oh, my god! I can't believe I judged someone by their appearance!
人を見た目で判断するなんて
I'm so sorry!
ごめんなさい
It's okay. I'm used to it.
いいけど慣れてるし
でかくなくても
Even if I'm not tall,
I can fly!
俺は飛べる
Hinata, don't you need to copy this down?
日向お前これ写さなくていいのか
Oh, yeah.
皆でかくて強そうなんだ
Everyone's so tall and looks really strong,
でも試合してるとそういうやつらと戦てるて分かる
but when we play them,
I feel like I can really take them on.
わくわくするぞくぞくする
It's exciting and nerve-racking.
It's amazing that you can stand toe-to-toe with them.
すごいねそんな人達と戦うなんて
じゃ日向は小さな巨人だね
That makes you a Little Giant, Hinata.
Huh?!
What?!
You know who the Little Giant is?
小さな巨人知てんの
Huh?
Uh, no. Um...
いやこうスポツとかで
When there's a Japanese person performing well among all the tall foreigners, aren't they all called that?
大きい外国人選手に混じて活躍してる日本人とか
そう呼んだりしない
Oh, right.
Yeah.
そう俺小さな巨人になるんだ
I'm gonna be the Little Giant.
おい東京に行けない小さな巨人ささとこれ写せよ
Hey, Little Giant who's not gonna make it to Tokyo at this rate, hurry up and copy this.
Class 1-5
また勉強教えてくれる
Will you help us study again?
Sure. Teaching you guys helps me remember the material too.
教えると自分も覚えるしね
ありがとうありがとう谷地さん
Oh, no, it's nothing...
Thanks! Thank you, Yachi!
じゃまた部活でな
See you at practice!
何だろうこれ
What is this?
I feel like I've been left out in direct sunlight for a while.
直射日光浴び続けた気分
Yachi!
谷地さん
午後の英語の小テストさき教えてもらたとこ出て
Stuff you taught me showed up in the English quiz this afternoon!
I got a whole third of them right!
３分の１も点取れた
Wahoo!
That's amazing, Hinata Shouyou!
日向くんすごい
Hinata's so good at communicating.
日向のコミュニケション能力の高さよ
日向ていいてば
I said just Hinata is fine!
日向すごい
That's amazing, Hinata!
They're already buddies.
もう仲良くなてる
一二三四
You'll just be observing today.
じゃ今日は見学だね緊張しなくていいからね
You don't have to be nervous.
五六七八
しゃち
Wight!
二二三四
しゃち
"Wight"?
Oh, and be careful of stray balls flying at you.
五六七八
でも流れダマには気をつけてね
Right!
流れダマまさか暗殺
Stray balls flying at me?
Could it be someone's trying to kill me?
君大丈夫
Hey, are you okay?
Th-The scary guy from yesterday!
き昨日のおかない人暗殺される
He's gonna kill me!
Um, I'm actually the coach...
あの一応俺コチなんだが
なんてこた
Oh, my god! I judged someone by their appearance again!
また見た目で人を判断してしまた
I'm so sorry!
すいませんでした
レフト
Left!
All right!
しゃあ
Nice, Tanaka!
ナイス田中
Close the gaps in your block!
ブロク隙間空けんな
Yes, sir!
次
Next!
すんません
I'm sorry!
I can't hear you guys!
レフト
Left!
Two blockers!
ブロク二枚
日向ナイス
Nice job, Hinata!
すみません
Sorry!
大丈夫
Are you okay?
Uh, yes.
This is my first time seeing volleyball up and close outside of PE class.
体育じゃないバレこんな近くで見るの初めてでして
It's pretty amazing.
すごい迫力です
うちは攻撃力なら県でもトプクラスだと思うよ
I think our team's offense is among the best in the prefecture.
すんません
Sorry!
Kiyoko's talking! She's smiling! Her lips are moving!
潔子さんがしゃべとる笑とるお口動いとる
あれがガルズトクてやつなのか
So that's what two girls talking looks like.
ふわふわしてんじゃねぇぞこら
Stop goofing off, damn it!
Come on, next round!
Karasuno was actually good enough to go to nationals before.
烏野はね昔は全国大会行けるくらい強かたの
こらすぐ次行くぞ
Yes, sir...
Nationals?
全国
But in the last few years, people have called us "the fallen champs" or "the clipped crows."
でもここ数年は「落ちた強豪」「飛べない烏」なんて呼ばれてきた
今度こそ行くんだ全国の舞台
This time, we're going to appear
on the national stage.
すごいすごいな私とは違うな
That's amazing...
So amazing!
Totally different from me.
集合
Gather 'round!
So, this is rather sudden,
明日ですが急遽
but Ougi West High School requested a
practice match tomorrow, and I accepted.
扇西高校から練習試合の申し入れがありましたので
お受けしました
インタハイ予選を見てぜひとのことでした
They saw us at the interhigh prelims and insisted.
青城に負けた悔しさも苦さも忘れるな
Don't forget the regret and bitterness of losing to Seijou.
However,
でも負ける感覚だけはいらねぇ
you don't need to hold onto the feeling of losing.
ととと払拭して来い
Hurry up and wipe that away!
Yeah!
Is Ougi West good?
扇西て強ぇのかな
It doesn't matter who we're facing.
どこだろうが関係ねぇ
All right. Let's do this!
よしゃあやるぞオラ
Every since that new girl came,
Kiyoko seems to have a different air about her.
１年ガル来てから潔子さん雰囲気変わたよな
Yeah! It must've been hard to talk, surrounded by all us guys!
きと男だらけでしゃべりづらかたんだ
これからは俺達も女子力を磨いていこうぜノヤち
From now on, we need to work on our feminine side, Noyacchi!
You got it, Ryuu-Ryuu!
オケ龍たん
If you talk like that, I'm never speaking to you.
それだと一切しゃべらないから
Episode Three:
Townperson B
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ村人Ｂ
"Townperson B."